在這個瞬息萬變的世界中，最大的風險是不承擔任何風險
唯一可以保證失敗的策略就是不承擔風險
謝謝，先生
Thank you, Sir.
非常感謝
Thank you, so much.
先生，您的 BuyEasy 做的很出色…… 您真是太棒了
Sir, great job at BuyEasy... Fantastic you are
謝謝你
Thank you.
同時祝賀您拿到第二輪融資
And sir, congratulations for your second round investment too.
是這樣的，先生，我在一家電商網站工作……
Actually sir, I work for an e-commerce website...
我是那裏的産品經理
...and I am a category manager there and I...
你可以把你的簡曆上傳到我們網站的求職闆塊
You can upload your resume on career section on our website.
先生，我可以找個時間給您看下我的作品嗎……-好的，再見
Sir, can I show you my work sometime... -OK, bye.
求你了，先生……請給我一次機會，先生
Please sir... Give me one chance, sir.
這些人，都不讓你在自己的派對上好好喝酒
Guys like these, don't even let you drink at your own party.
巴蒂，你用20%的股份賣了多少錢？5000萬？
Bhati, how much did you get for 20%, 50?
周日的商業前景上會公佈的……到時候你就知道了
It will be out in Sunday's Business Outlook... Take a look yourself!
巴蒂，快告訴我，6000萬？
Bhati, tell me, 60?
這是官方數據，我現在不能透露
It's official, I can't reveal it now.
多少錢，7500萬？
How much, 75?
別告訴我是一億！
Now don't tell me it's 100.
媽的! ! ！
F**K!!!
一億？
100?
一個億？
A hundred million?
巴蒂，你公司的估價是五億美元？
Bhati, your company's evaluation is half a billion dollars?
媽的! ! ！
F**K!!!
這有什麼大不了的？
So what's the big deal?
還比 Flipkart 少了75億美元呢
It's still lesser than Flipkart by 7.5 billion.
巴蒂，這意味著我的一個大四的同學要成為億萬富翁了！
Bhati, it means one of my college seniors is going to be a billionaire!
真他媽幸運！
F**K, what luck!
這與命運或運氣無關……
It's not about fate or luck...
印度管理學院？
IIM?
印度管理學院史瑞拉姆夫人女子學院
LSR. IIM.
我應該作為 CAT 出場的
I should have appeared for CAT.
你所做的一切，就是喋喋不休地談論我的運氣
All you do, is keep harping about my luck.
你已經把你的創業想法跟我說過無數次了
You've told me about your start-up idea over a 100 times now.
你為什麼著手去做？
Why don't you do something about it?
一個新的矽穀正在這裏崛起
A new Silicon Valley is being upstaged at Hiranandani here.
而你卻仍然在 Mokart 上銷售那些廉價的山寨手機
And you are still selling these cheap chinese phones on Mokart.
- 他們很有說服力，巴蒂 - 胡說
They're exculsive, Bhati. -Bullshit.
老弟，冇那麼簡單
Son, its not that easy.
辭掉你的工作，出去創業
Leave your job and venture into the market.
然後你就會知道，命運到底是由什麼組成的
And then you will learn, what destinies are made of and from.
老弟你搞什麼? 還在喝第一杯啤酒？
Dude, what the f**k? Still on your first beer?
快點喝完！
Down it!
我不喝了，巴蒂
I'm good, Bhati.
再給他來杯啤酒
Beer for him.
巴蒂，我8:30要早起上班
Bhati, I have to wake up early at 8:30 for work.
閉嘴! ! ！
Shut up!!!
巴蒂，我現在已經變得非常自律了
Bhati, I've become very discipled now.
甚至不需要鬨鍾就能醒來
Nowadays I don't even need an alarm to wake up..
不去上班嗎？
Not going to the office?
你在這兒幹什麼？
What are you doing here?
我開了熱水器
I switched on the geyser
正在燒水
The water's still heating up.
曼達爾，你為什麼在我的浴室裏洗澡？
Mandal why do you take a bath in my bathroom?
我的桶把手壞了
The handle of my bucket is broken.
那你可以把我的桶拿到你的浴室去啊
So, take my bucket to your bathroom.
實際上，我今天想洗個淋浴
Actually, I feel like taking a shower today.
大哥，你完全可以在自己的浴室洗淋浴啊
Dude, you can take a shower even in your own bathroom.
一定是水燒好了了！
The water must've heated up!
至少別用我的毛巾啊
Atleast spare my towel.
Mokart 把我坑慘了，巴蒂，從頭坑到尾
Mokart f**ked me over Bhati. Completely f**ked me.
我為這個巴西的項目付出了很多努力
I put in so much effort into this Brazil project.
甚至周日也加班工作
Worked even on Sundays.
我至少做了1000個 ppt
I made atleast a 1000 PPTs.
做了超過5000張錶格
Must've made more than 5000 excel sheets.
當需要指定項目負責人的時候，竟然冇選我，他們另外派人去裏約
And when it came down to leading the team, instead of me, they sent someone else to Rio.
巴蒂，我要報仇！
Bhati, I will take revenge!
我一定要報仇！
I will take revenge for sure!
我一定會找他們報仇的，巴蒂
I will even avenge them, Bhati.
一旦我拿到融資
Once I get the funding
我會賺很多錢，巴蒂... 很多錢
I'll make so much money Bhati... So much money
我要把Mokart買下來，然後……
I'll buy Mokart and...
然後在 OLX 上賣了，操他媽的
And sell it on OLX, f**king shit.
但是我要怎麼做呢，巴蒂？
But how, Bhati?
我怎樣才能融到錢，巴蒂？
How will I get the funding, Bhati?
不是每個人的運氣都像你那麼好
Everyone's luck isn't as good as your's.
你是什麼？
What are you?
什麼意思？
What do you mean, what am I?
你是什麼？
What are you?
我是mokart. com的區域經理，納文·班薩爾
I am the Executive Regional Manager, Navin Bansal, Mokart.com
不，你是什麼？
No, what are YOU?
-區域經理…… -你是啤酒
Executive regional manager... -You are a beer.
什麼意思？
What do you mean?
你是啤酒，混蛋
You're beer, motherf**ker.
你是啤酒
You're beer.
這個瓶子呢? 這是你的公司
And this bottle here? This is your company
你以為，如果你能到玻璃杯裏麵
You think, you'll get into the glass.
你會玩得很開心
You will have fun.
不是嗎？
Isn't it?
但是看看這個
But look at this.
看到了嗎？
Can you see?
你實際上不想離開啤酒瓶
You actually don't want to leave the bottle.
想把啤酒倒進杯子裏，它需要先離開啤酒瓶
For the beer to get into the glass... It needs to leave the bottle first
一旦你從瓶子裏出來
Once you're out of the bottle
你就可以進入任何你想要的玻璃杯
Then you can get into any glass you want.
可以是這個杯子，如果你想要的話
In this glass, if you want.
或者你也可以到這個玻璃杯
Or you can get into this glass
-甚至是在這個杯子裏 -這是一個葡萄酒杯
Even in this glass. -Its a wine glass.
你怎麼知道的？
How the hell do YOU know that?
你是啤酒
You are beer.
明白了嗎？
Get it?
你想去哪兒就去哪兒
You can go wherever you want.
明白嗎？
Understand?
但是首先你得從瓶子裏出來
But it's quintissential you come out of the bottle, first.
一旦你出來了，你可以裝滿一半的杯子
Once you are out, you could fill half the glass
也可能不會
Or maybe you won't.
但是如果你不出來
But if you don't come out
那你肯定填不滿，看到了嗎
Then you'll definitely not be able to fill it. Look here.
你的工作不是問問題
And its not your job to ask the questions.
你是啤酒
You're beer.
你的工作就是流動
And your job is to flow.
你是啤酒
You are beer.
這是啤酒
This is beer.
不是玻璃杯
Not glass.
事實上冇有玻璃杯
Infact there is no glass.
但是桌子上有一個玻璃杯，巴蒂
But there is a glass on the table, Bhati.
冇有
No glass.
我是啤酒，巴蒂
I am a beer, Bhati.
我是啤酒
I am beer.
我要從啤酒瓶裏出來
And I'll get out of the bottle.
我會從瓶子裏出來……
I will get out of the bottle...
你要吃早餐嗎？
Will you have breakfast?
嗯
Yes
你想吃什麼？
What do you want to eat?
麵包 煎蛋卷
Bread Omlett.
我們冇有雞蛋了
We've no eggs left.
麵包 果醬
Bread Jam.
哪種，混合水果還是芒果？
Which one, mixed fruit or mango?
混合水果
Mixed fruit.
混合水果上個星期就冇有了！
The mixed fruit one, got done with, last week itself!
那就芒果吧！
Mango then!
我們根本就冇有芒果果醬！
We didn't get any mango in the first place!
就給我烤麵包吧
Just toast the bread for me.
烤麵包機已經壞了很久了
The toaster's been broken for such a long time, now!
老哥，我就喝杯茶就夠了
Dude, one cup tea will do.
但我已經把所有的牛奶都用來做凝乳了！
But I already used all the milk for the curd!
那你在吃什麼？
So what are you eating, then?
凝乳
Curd.
我今天不想吃早餐，我要直接跳到午餐！
I don't want any breakfast today. I'll have directly skip to lunch!
什麼？
What?
早餐是一天中最重要的一餐
Breakfast is the most important meal of the day.
你的"電池"會開始滲漏，你母親…… -老哥，請讓我一個人靜一靜
Your 'battery' will start seeping. Your mom.... -Dude, please leave me alone.
-怎麼了？-巴蒂……你是對的！
What? -Bhati... You were right!
什麼？
What?
我是啤酒，巴蒂
I'm beer, Bhati.
我會從酒瓶裏出來
And I will flow out of the bottle.
我會辭職
I will resign.
我會辭職的
這個決定會改變你的生活
This decision will change your life.
來吧，我們喝一杯
Come on, lets drink.
給他一杯啤酒
One beer for him.
巴蒂，聽著，巴蒂
Bhati listen, Bhati.
先聽我說
First listen to me
你現在做的這個決定
This decision that you're taking now
會改變你的未來
Will change your future.
你懂我的意思
You know what I mean.
不! ! 不! ! 不! ! 你冇明白我的意思
No!! No!! No!! You didn't get me.
我現在就辭職
I will resign right now.
我馬上給他打電話
I will call him right now.
- 你瘋了嗎?-我現在就辭職我才不管
-Have you gone mad? -I will resign right now, I don't give a F**K.
- 聽我說-我馬上給他打電話
-Listen to me. -I will call him right now.
聽我說
-Listen to me.
巴蒂，我是啤酒 巴蒂，讓我流動
Bhati, I am beer Bhati, let me flow.
兄弟，不要流這麼多！
Bro, don't flow so much!
聽我說，聽我說
Listen to me, just listen.
等白天再打電話
You have to serve the notice period.
你覺得我會害怕嗎？
Do you think, I'm scared?
我是個懦夫嗎？
Am I a coward?
我什麼時候說過..
When did I say that...
我會證明給你看，我會證明給你看
I will show it to you. I will prove it to you.
-我現在就給你看 -納文，現在的時間非常尷尬
I will show it to you, right now. -Navin. Listen, listen. This a very odd hour, right now.
你以為我不能從瓶子裏出來嗎? 我是啤酒，我會流..
You think I can't get out of the bottle? I am a beer and I will flow...
拉傑？
Rajat?
拉傑，很抱歉這個時候打電話給你
Rajat, I am so sorry that I am calling you this hour.
有件非常重要的事，我想告訴你！
There's something very important, I want to tell you!
拉傑，你是個混蛋! ! ！
Rajat you're an a**hole!!!
還有你的部門
And your department
事實上，你的整個公司就是一個糞坑
Infact your whole company, is an a**hole.
所以你和你的公司可以從我的生活中消失了
So you and your company are fired from my life.
晚安，拉傑 · 欣德
Good night, Jai Hind.
去你媽的
And F**K you.
去你的! ! ！
F**K YOU!!!
那是我的酒！
That's my drink!!!
對不起..
Sorry...
真的嗎? 你是印度管理學院的？
Really? Are you from IIM?
這是誰？
Whose this?
先生
親愛的先生
敬愛的先生，我真的很抱歉
什麼事，八卦？
Yaa Chatty, tell me
但是美國國家航空航天局秘密會議的結果應該在下周公佈，不是嗎？
But NasCom conclave's result where supposed to be out next week, weren't they?
阿克希爾，誰？
Akhil, who?
哦，那個家夥
Ohh the hostel 4 guy.
他在納斯康嗎？
Is he in Nascom?
好的
OK.
那麼... 他說了什麼？
So..What did he say?
開什麼玩笑！
You've got to be kidding me!
你確定嗎？
Are you sure?
確認？
Confirmed?
我的 b 計畫會被選中嗎？
My B-Plan is going to get selected?
媽的! ! ！
F**K!!!
真幸運！
What luck!
你確定嗎？
Are you sure?
謝謝，謝謝，謝謝老哥
Thanks, thanks, thanks dude...
那好吧，我會告訴其他人
Ok then, I'll tell the others as well
不，等正式公佈之後我再更新狀態
No, no.. Let it get official first. I'll update my status after!
好的
OK.
我晚上再和你談，好嗎？
I'll talk to you in the evening, alright?
好的，保重，再見
Ok. Take care. Bye.
小文文
Naveen
你真是個不負責任的人
You are so irresponsible man.
這東西就在你的馬桶後麵
This was lying behind your commode.
我該怎麼處理它？
What do I do with it?
拜托你件事，曼達爾
Now do one thing Mandal.
這個? 扔到垃圾桶裏去！
This? Throw it into the garbage!
合理分配時間，你是公司非常重要的員工
節約用水，你是公司非常重要的員工
他把我叫到辦公室，開始對我大喊大叫！
He called me in the office and started yelling at me!
我說”先生
I said, "Sir
……如果你對我的睡眠時間有疑問
..if you have so much problem with me sleeping..
那麼你應該把我轉到人力資源部
..then tranfer me to HR department..
他們甚至可以得到額外的睡眠獎勵”
They even get an extra bonus for sleeping, there"
吸煙有害健康，你是公司非常重要的員工
傑圖 兄弟！
Jeetu bro!
恭喜..
Congrats...
還有煙嗎？
Do you have an extra?
冇了，這是最後一支
No, it's the last one.
冇事，把煙吹到我臉上
No issue. Blow it on my face.
被動抽兩口也行
Passive will also do!
恭喜什麼？
Congrats for what?
別裝了
Now don't pretend!
你的評估太棒了！
You were amazing in the appraisal!
順便問一下，你看了昨晚的《納克 · 巴利耶》嗎？
By the way, did you watch last night's Nach Baliye??
切坦 · 巴加特很棒，他隻是... ..
Chetan bhagat was awesome. He just..
你是怎麼知道的？
How did you get to know about it?
昨晚看的，晚上9點的節目
Saw it last night. The 9pm show.
然後又看了11:30的重播
And then again, the 11:30 repeat telecast.
不，我是說評估，你怎麼知道的？
No, I mean about the appraisal. How do you know about that?
評估? 哦! ！
Appraisal ? Ohh!!!
喬希先生給我們看過
Joshi sir showed it to us.
即便是“成就箱”也不夠大
Even the 'Acheivement box' wasn't big enough.
雖然我什麼都冇得到過
Though I didn't really get one thing!
但是為什麼你在自我評價中給自己打了4分？
Why did you gave yourself 4 out of 5 in the self evaluation?
我就知道! 我應該給自己3.5..
I knew it! I should've given myself 3.5...
3.5分？
3.5?
你應該給自己5分
You should've given yourself 5 out of 5.
還不夠完美嗎？
What more could you possibly do?
告訴我，你還能做些什麼？
No tell me, what more can you do?
傑圖，我能告訴你一些事情嗎？
Jeetu, can I tell you something?
每當我們拿到你寫的代碼
Whenever we get a code written by you
我們直接上傳，都不用測試
We forward it, without even testing it
為什麼要浪費時間呢？
Why waste time, by running it?
喬希先生一直稱贊你
And Joshi sir keeps praising you always.
對了，市場部的迪維亞
Oh, Divya from the marketing team?
今天是她的訂婚日
It's her engagement today.
你會來嗎？
Will you come?
喬希先生說了什麼？
What was Joshi sir saying?
喬希先生說，他會來的！
Joshi sir said, he will come!
實際上……
Actually what happened was...
不是 我是說喬希先生說我什麼了？
No!!! No!! I meant what was Joshi sir saying about me?
你剛才說的……
You said something...
哦
Ohh
不僅是喬希先生
Not only Joshi sir
而是整個部門都這麼說
But the whole department says this.
"不管別人怎麼樣，你一定會升職的"
"Whether or not someone else does... you are defintely getting promoted"
冇有別的可能
And there's no two ways about it.
好了，我該走了，我還有工作要做
OK!!! I should be going, I have work to do.
吃塊口香糖
Take a chewing gum.
- 不用了 -是薄荷味的
-No!!! No!! -Its mint flavoured.
不了，你自己吃吧
No, no.. You can have it.
好的，過幾個小時我也走了，我要休息一下了
Ok!!! I will also leave after a couple of hours, I have to rest.
太多的工作要做……
Too much work to do...
明天別忘了吃甜蛋餅
And remember the mithaee kachori for tommorow!
嚮你的妻子問好
And greetings to your wife.
夥計，你看到那家夥了嗎？
Dude, did you see that guy?
真牛批
Amazing
等一下……給我整一口
Just a second... Pass me the cigarette
納文：兄dei，五點見，很重要的事
主席先生，職員要求將午餐時間由十五分鍾延長至半小時
Sir, the staff has requested the lunch time to be extended from 15 minutes to half an hour.
拒絕
Denied
讓他們保持饑餓和愚蠢，下一個
Let them stay hungry and stay foolish. Next.
提供給技術支持團隊的筆記本電腦有故障
The laptops that were given to the TechSupport team are faulty.
電池隻用了半小時就冇電了
The batteries drain out in half an hour!
給他們十個充電寶，讓他們充滿活力
Give them 10 of these and get them energized
先生，但他們需要給筆記本電腦充電，不是手機
Sir, but they need to charge their laptops. not phones.
那就告訴該死的技術支持去幫助技術支持，下一個
Well then tell the f**king tech support to help tech support, in all the matters of tech support. Next.
先生，市場調查報告
Sir, marketing research report.
不要給數字，給我圖像和餅圖
Don't give numbers, give me graphs and pie charts.
你! ！
You!!
明天把這個圖錶做好發給我
Give me the graphs on this by tommorow.
但我是法律部的
But I am from Legal.
反對無效
Objection Overruled.
下一個
Next.
先生，所有新來的銷售實習生都在等待入職
Sir, all the new sales interns are waiting for their induction
叫他們在會議室集合
Assemble them in conference room.
但是先生，那個房間的空調壞了，裏麵很熱
But sir, the AC in that room is not working. It's very hot in there.
很好，這是他們需要感受熱量的第一天
Good, it's the first day they need to feel the heat.
先生，你的脫發預約怎麼辦？
Sir, but what about your hair loss appointment?
讓我們為恰恰熱烈鼓掌
Let's give a big round of applause for chacha.
你們是公司未來的銷售團隊
So, you guys are the company's future sales team.
你們直接和客戶打交道
And you guys will be dealing with the client directly.
- 你們興奮嗎? -是的，先生
-Are you guys excited? -Yes sir.
好
OK!!!
我跟你們講
So guys, let me tell you.
給客戶留下深刻印象就像是
Impressing your client is like impressing a girl
在給鎮上所有男人都在追的女孩留下深刻印象
that every man in the town is after.
而這個女孩，根本不想見你
And this girl, doesn't even want to meet you.
不想接你的電話
Doesn't want to pick up your calls.
事實上，她根本不認識你
Infact, she doesn't even know you.
她討厭你
She f**king hates you.
現在，你要怎麼做才能打動這樣一個女孩呢？
Now, what will you do to impress such a girl?
先生，我會威脅說要割腕，先生
Sir, I will threaten to slit my wrists, sir.
也許可以作為達到目標的最後手段
Yeah, maybe, as a last resort to meet the targets.
但是，你會從什麼開始呢？
But, what will you begin with?
你永遠不放棄! ! ！
You will never give up!!!
你永遠不會罷休
You will never quit!!!
你必須像對待你的女朋友一樣對待你的客戶
You have to treat your client, like your girlfriend.
嚮他們展示你的忠誠
Show them your loyalty.
帶他們出去喝咖啡
Take them out for coffee.
一天三次
Call them thrice a day.
記住他們的生日
Remember their birthdays.
甚至每天晚上打飛機的時候都要想著你的客戶
In fact, fantasize about your client every night.
好的，先生，每！天！晚！上！
I do sir. EVERY. SINGLE. NIGHT.
好 太好了
OK!!! Excellent.
不管怎樣
Anyways..
你們要記得
Guys remember.
無論發生什麼..
Whatever happens..
不管情況如何
Whatever the situation may be.
就像我……
Just like me...
永不放棄
You should never quit.
大聲點可以嗎? 你應該...-永不放棄
Can I hear that aloud? You should... -never quit.
你應該...-永不放棄
You should... -never quit.
You should... -never quit
方案B有戲，我辭職了，五點見
你應該...-永不放棄
You should... -never quit
方案B有戲，我辭職了，五點見
你應該...-永不放棄
You should... -never quit
夥計們！
Guys!!!
我放棄了！
I quit!!!
你應該..
You should...
但是消息已經被證實了，不是嗎？
But the news is confirmed, isn't it?
嗯，阿克希爾在 NasCom 工作，他曾在4號酒店
Yaa, Akhil works at NasCom itself. He was in hostel 4
四號酒店的人都很好，很有幫助
Hostel 4 guys are very nice. Very helpful.
去年，我扇了魯奇父親一巴掌
Last year, when I slapped Ruchi's father
四號酒店的 G.sec 把我保釋出來了
Hostel 4's G.sec bailed me out.
不，不，我已經買了
No, no. I bought it already.
玉米也買了
I've bought babycorn as well.
嘿，傑圖
Hey Jitu.
嗯，嗯……
yaa, yaa...
冇有，我還是冇買到醋栗
No, I still didn't get any gooseberry.
嗯，我再找找
Yaa, I will look for them...
我一小時後回家，好嗎？
I'll be home in an hour. OK?
好的 好的
OK!!! OK!!!
夥計，蔬菜太貴了! ! ！
Dude, vegetables are SO expensive!!!
你知道玉米要多少錢嗎？
Do you know how much babycorn costs?
100克100盧比，每公斤1000盧比
100 gram for 100 Rupees. 1000 per KG.
要花錢的地方太多了! 最近大家都在聊什麼？孟買的房價又漲了
We need money in life, dude! What do people keep going on about, real estate being expensive in Bombay?
我辭職了 - 別吃蘋果，老哥 他們貼了一張30塊錢的標簽，卻收我50塊
Jitu I quit the job. -Don't eat the apple dude. They put a sticker of 30 on it but sell it for 50...
你怎麼？你剛說什麼？
What did you leave? What are you saying?
我昨晚辭職了
I quit my job, last night.
為什麼？
Why?
巴西呢？
-And Brazil?
他們派別人去了
-They are sending someone else.
現在怎麼辦？
What now?
新工作? 還是什麼？
New job? What?
不，我們的方案會在秘密會議上被選中
No dude, our idea is going to get selected in the conclave.
開始創業吧
Now let's just begin with the start-up
我們三年前就開始討論這個問題了-納文，我們已經討論過這個問題了
We've only been talking about it since 3rd year. -Naveen we've already discussed this.
我們討論了什麼？
What did we discuss?
一年半之後，等你從巴西回來的時候
That by the time you come back from Brazil, after a
尤吉先在這裏打通渠道
year and a half, Yogi will make some contacts here.
但是我們可以... -而且我也必須和桑亞安定下來
But that we can do... -And even I have to settle down with Somya.
理解我一下，我現在不能辭職
Guys try to understand, I can't leave my job right now.
公司裏終於有好事發生了
There's finally something good happening for me in the company
大家開始意識到我的潛力
People are realizing my potential.
我是公司的重要員工
I’m a valuable employee to the company.
-我不能辭職-聽我說
Won't be able to leave the job. - Listen to me.
一個新的矽穀正在這裏崛起
A new Silicon Valley is being upstaged at Hiranandani here!
而你卻還在用 Python 寫代碼
And you're still writing codes on Python.
這就是機會，這就是時機，我們應該現在就開始
This the the opportunity. This is the time. We should start now.
別擔心，夥計
And don't worry at all dude.
一旦我們拿到融資，我保證，即使我們都不拿錢，你的薪水絕對不會少
Once we get the funding, we'll ensure, you get your salary even if we work for free.
傑圖，所有的核心工作都和技術有關
Jitu, all the core work is tech related.
冇有你我們怎麼辦？
How will we manage without you?
他想說的是如果我們想成為超級企業家
All he's trying to say is, if we want to be the 'stud' enterpreneurs
並且想讓我們的公司能像蘋果一樣大
and want our company to be as big as Apple...
那麼他需要成為史蒂夫 · 喬佈斯
Then he needs to be Steve Jobs
你需要成為史蒂夫 · 沃茲尼亞克
You need to be Steve Wozniak
我要成為肖恩 · 帕克
and I need to be a Sean Parker.
肖恩 · 帕克是Facebook的人
Sean Parker's from Facebook.
嗯，我們都辭去工作，成為企業家
Yaa, we'll leave our jobs and become entrepreneurs.
你會寫企業家精神這個詞嗎？
Can you even spell entrepreneurship?
E
N
T...
要成為一個企業家，你不需要會拚寫，有創業精神就夠了
To be an entrepreneur, you don't need the spelling but the spirit.
納文，現在終於有好事發生在我的生活中了！
Naveen, its now that finally something good's happening in my life!
我的評估很難！
I've got an appraisal with such difficulty!
但我得了5分！
I got scored 5 out of 5 in my evaluation!
這就是我要說的，5分就是你工作的極限了 然後呢？ 你不會得到超過5分的分數
Thats what I am saying, 5 is the limit of your job. What after then? You won't score anything above 5.
你是否想要度過隻有5分的人生？
Do you want to get through life, only scoring 5 out of 5?
聽著，我給你解釋一下……
Listen, I will explain it to you...
你是什麼？
What are you?
我是什麼? 我是傑圖，已婚IT男，還有什麼？
What am I? I am Jitu, married and what else?
不! 不! 你是什麼？
No!!No!!1 What ARE you?
你是什麼？
What are you?
你瘋了嗎，納文？
Are you out of your mind , Naveen?
你是咖啡
You're Coffee.
什麼？
-What?
你是咖啡，混蛋
You're coffee, Motherf**ker.
你是咖啡..
You are coffee...
這個杯子是你的公司
And this cup is your company.
現在你以為你可以享受鑽進玻璃杯的樂趣……
Now you think you'lll have fun getting into the glass...
但是你不想離開咖啡杯
But you don't want to leave the cup.
現在如果你想流進玻璃杯裏，你必須先從咖啡杯裏出來
Now if you want to flow into the glass, you have to get out of the cup first.
等會……
Easy. Easy.
你到底想說什麼？
What do you want to say exactly?
我想說的是，一旦你出去了，你就可以進入這個玻璃杯..
All I'm saying is, once you're out, you can go into this glass...
你可以鑽進這個玻璃杯
You can get into this glass.
或者這個..
Or this...
現在你可能會想"這是個糖碗……
Now you might think, "This is a sugar bowl
但我是咖啡，我怎麼才能進去呢? ”
but I am coffee. How can I get inside this?"
不是嗎？
Won't you?
但你怎麼知道? 你是咖啡..
But how do YOU know? You're coffee...
老哥，你在幹什麼？
Dude, what are doing?
對不起，對不起，對不起..
Sorry, Sorry, Sorry, Sorry...
你在幹什麼? 我的手機..
What are you doing dude? My phone...
如果是啤酒的話就會順利多了……
It happened so well, with a beer!
我想說的是..
So, what I was trying to say is...
不管你想說什麼，跟別人說去吧
Whatever you want to say, tell it to someone else
你辭掉了工作
You've left your job and let go
你以為你就是喬佈斯了嗎？
What do you think, you're Steve Jobs?
-我想說的是...-首先，自己先理清楚，你想做什麼..
What I was trying to say is... -First, figure it out for yourself, what you want to do...
然後我們再談
We'll then sit and talk it down
但是你要去哪裏呢？
But where are you going?
去買醋栗！
To buy gooseberry!
我明白..
I understood...
是的
Yeah.
那個混蛋有一天打電話給我說
The f**ker called me the other day and said
“為什麼總是拿人力資源團隊開玩笑？
"Why do keep joking about the H.R. team?
你知道做一個人力資源經理需要多少天賦嗎? ”
Do you know how much talent it takes, to be an H.R. manager?"
我說”先生
I said, "Sir
一天睡22個小時..
To sleep for 22 hours a day...
絕對需要很多天賦! ”
definitely takes a lot of talent!"
你的拉鏈開了！
Your fly's open!
他上當了！哈哈哈
He took the bait!
吸煙有害健康，你是公司非常重要的員工
傑圖 兄弟！
Jeetu bro!
恭喜恭喜恭喜！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
我很高興，我拍了一張帶有打印輸出的自拍照。
I was so glad, I took a selfie with a printout.
恭喜你！
Kudos!
那麼……
So...
傑圖德拉 · 馬赫什瓦裏 先生！
Mr. Jitendra Maheshwari!
高級開發工程師！
Mr. Senior Developer!
你不請我抽支煙嗎？
Won't you offer me a cigarette?
但是這根快抽完了
But this one's almost done...
把剩下的都給我吧
Just give me whatever's left of it.
明天以後，我就再也見不到你了！
Tomorrow onwards, I won't be able to even see you!
重要的崗位
A big position!
薪水更高了
A big salary! The works!
你告訴你妻子了嗎？
Did you tell your wife about it?
還冇有，我回家後會告訴她的！
Not yet. I'll tell her once I get home!
哎喲
Ahaan!
今晚有人要走運了! ! ！
Someone's gonna get lucky tonight!!!
傑圖 兄弟..
Jeetu bro...
我能告訴你一些事情嗎？
Can I tell you something?
幹得漂亮！
Amazing job!
你的生活現在已經完全安定下來了！
Your life's now absolutely set!
在接下來的5年裏，你將成為
Within the next 5 years, you'll be
首席架構師
Principal Developer
然後在接下來的十年裏
Then within the next 10 years
副總
Associate Divsion Head
15年後，我敢肯定，你會取代喬希先生！
And 15 years down, I'm sure, you'd have replaced Joshi Sir!
喬希先生! ! ！
Joshi Sir!!!
我剛才在誇獎您！
I was just praising you!
不，真的！
No, genuinely!
喬希先生
Joshi Sir.
你要口香糖嗎？
Will you have a chewing gum?
口香糖？
Chewing gum?
不，我得回去了，我還有工作要做
No. I've to go back. I've work to do.
我帶來了超級薄荷口味的，特別為你準備的
I brought the 'Advance mint' flavoured ones, especially for you.
薄荷糖或者超級薄荷糖，我剛剛告訴你了，我不想要！
Mint or advance mint. I just told you, I don't want any!
我要回去，我有工作要做！
I'll take a leave. I've work to do!
那好吧，不管怎樣，今天開始新的工作了！
Alright then. Anyway, new work starts today for you!
我們晚上在潘德基的攤位上見麵，吃點甜蛋卷
Let's meet at Pandeji's stall in the evening for some mithaee kachori.
下午6點！
6 PM!
好的 到時再說……
Ok!!! I'll let you know...
別想了! 就這麼定了，好嗎？
Don't think about it! It's final, OK?
怎麼樣？
What's up?
升職通知
傑圖德拉 · 馬赫什瓦裏 開發工程師
傑圖德拉 · 馬赫什瓦裏 高級開發工程師
我剛回來，這些公關真的把你的生活搞得一團糟！
I just got back, these PR guys really suck the life out of you!
拉傑，我能進來嗎？
Rajat, can I come in?
我怎麼知道？要7點才結束
How would I know, it'll take till 7?
拉傑什！
Rajesh!
好的，我... 我會去的，我會去的，給我幾分鍾
OK.. I'll... I'll be there, I'll be there. Just give me a couple of minutes.
好嗎？
OK?
再見
Bye.
那麼……納文
So, Naveen.
那晚你喝了多少酒？
How many drink did you have that night?
我真的很抱歉，拉傑
I am really sorry, Rajat.
我... 我真的很尷尬
I'm... I'm really embarassed about it.
發生那些事情
For whatever happened.
在巴西項目之後我真的很沮喪，所以我喝醉了，我..
After Brazil project, I was really upset, so I got drunk and I...
但無論如何，我認為離開這份工作是正確的決定
But anyway I think leaving the job was the right decision.
但我真誠地為我所說的話道歉
But I sincererly apologize for the things that I said.
顯然我不是那個意思
Obviously I didn't mean any of that.
冇關係的，這件事……
It's OK!!! It happens...
我們已經一起工作了三年了，冇關係! ! ！
We've been working together for three years now. It's OK!!!
不要給自己太多壓力，放輕鬆
Don't stress more. Chill
謝謝你
Thank you.
我帶來了辭呈
I brought my resignation.
我隻是想..
I just thought...
這樣正式一些……
Officialy, I would...
那麼接下來呢？
What next, then?
就是這樣，我想創業，拉傑
Just that. Want to do a start-up, Rajat.
我們的 b 計劃進入了國家航天局秘密會議的最後一輪
Our B-Plan is in the final round of the NasCom Conclave
事實上，有99% 的可能性，它會... ... 被選中
Infact, there's a 99% chance, that it's going to... get selected
所以我隻能祈禱了
So I am just keeping my fingers crossed.
哇! 裸辭創業！
Wow! Full time start-up, then!
哇
Wow
那麼你可能會考慮過……
Then you may have thought about the...
天使投資者的流動性偏好
The liquidity preferences of the Angel Investors.
是嗎？
Yeah?
你一定也考慮過員工持股計劃的分配吧
You must've also thought about the ESOP pool allocation?
對吧？
Right?
不，還冇有
No. Not exactly!!!
但我相信，隨著時間的推移，我們都會考慮到
But I am sure with time we will get into it.
你知道拉胡爾 · 夏爾馬嘛？他是我大學時的室友
You know Rahul Sharma was my batchmate in college.
拉胡爾 · 夏爾馬！！
Rahul Sharma!!!
Micromax 的聯合創始人
The co-founder of Micromax.
哦，當然! 我讀了很多關於他的書，真的嗎？
Ohh, of course! I've read a lot, about him. Really?
當然! 當然! 你是企業家
Of course! Of course! You're the entrepreneur.
他就是這樣開始的... 創業
He'd started exactly like this... With a start-up
看看他今天在哪兒！
Look where he is today!
去年他的公司估值為..
Last year his company was valued at...
超過10億美元
...more then a billion dollars.
十億美元，我知道，我知道
Billion dollars, I know, I know.
你聽說過 Harshit Kothari 嗎？
Have you heard about Harshit Kothari?
他也是我的室友
He too, was my batchmate.
哈斯特？
Harshit?
冇聽過嗎？
No?
冇有
No...
不管怎樣，他也是從這樣的創業開始的
Anyway, even he began with the start-up like this
項目叫什麼來著..
What was it's name again...
不記得了，總之……
Anyway!
不幸的是... ... 想法很好，但效果不太好
Unfortunately... It was a good idea, but it didn't do so well.
冇過幾年，他必須回來..
He had to return...
回到他的工作崗位
To his job, in a couple of years.
我們那一屆還有很多這樣的人
There were many more, in my batch...
Manoj Agarwal... 他的兄弟 Vishal Agarwal
Manoj Agarwal... His brother, Vishal Agarwal
索拉佈 · 瓦希，r.k. 帕伊..
Saurabh Vahi, R.K. Paee...
克裏希那穆希
Krishnamurthy
你都聽說過嗎？
Have you heard about them all?
索拉佈 · 法希
Saurabh Vahi...
冇聽過
I don't think so.
當然，你現在可是大人物了！
Of course. You're in the big league now!
你將會贏得一場聲望很高的比賽！
You're going to win a prestigious competition!
這個比賽每年都舉行嗎？
Is this competition held every year?
是啊，已經舉辦了7-8年了
Yeah, it's been happening for the last 7-8 years now.
哇! 7-8年了！
Wow! 7-8 years!
那麼，之前的獲獎者中有多少人已經成功了呢？
So how many of the previous winners have made it big?
以前的贏家! ! ！
Previous winners!!!
其實我也不知道
I don't know actually.
每當這個國家的畢業生厭倦了朝九晚五的工作..
Whenever graduates of this country, get bored by their 9 to 5 jobs...
所以，為了擺脫睏境，他們隻有三個選擇
So, to get out, they come up with only three options for themselves.
讀MBA
MBA
讀IAS
IAS
或者去創業
or Start-Up.
出去看看，納文
Go out and take a look, Naveen.
創業公司的創始人們坐在三個小屋中的兩個裏麵
There are start-up founders sitting in 2 out of 3 cabins, out there.
納文..
Naveen...
你真的認為你的想法是百萬分之一嗎？
Do you really think your idea is one in a million?
聽著
Look!
你認為這是你所嚮往的……
You think this is your passion...
這就是為什麼，你要離開這份工作
And that is why, you're leaving this job.
但這不是…… 納文
But, this is not your passion, Naveen.
如果真的是這樣，那麼很久之前……
If this was your passion, then you would've left this job...
就辭職了
A long time back.
你不會等著被巴西項目拒絕
You wouldn't have waited for being rejected from the Brazil project.
不..
No...
不... 我不這樣認為
No...I don't
我覺得..
I think....
北京
Beijing.
我們準備開始在那裏擴張，比原計劃提前了6個月
We're beginning our expansion there, 6 months ahead of schedule.
一周內有個會議
Apointment within a week.
我們需要一個聰明人
We need someone smart over there...
像你一樣
Like you.
你要在20分鍾內……
You have to leave for your... Visa appointment, in Delhi in...
去德裏辦簽證
The next 20 mins.
那天晚上你打電話給我
That night when you called me.
你並冇有做出選擇
You did not make a choice.
你隻是錶現出拒絕
You were simply reacting to a rejection.
現在才是真正的選擇
Now is the real choice.
想想吧，納文
Think about it, Naveen.
已經得到的一定比不確定的更好
One in hand is obviously better than one not-so-sure in the bush.
不是嗎？
No?
傑圖：創業帶我一個，8點酒吧見麵？
尤吉：喲！你今天要喝啤酒
納文
Naveen
在我的浴室裏
In my bathroom.
你讓我不要用你的衛生間，我怎麼用？
How will I use your bathroom, after you've asked me not to?
什麼事？
Yeah, tell me?
真是奇怪啊
How strange is this?
納文冇有升職，所以辭職了
Naveen didn't get promoted, so he quit his job.
現在你卻想在升職後辭職
And now you're thinking of quitting, after you've been promoted.
人類的大腦是個謎，夥計
Human brain is a mystery, bud.
你想點些什麼嗎？
-You wanna order something?
你想點什麼？
What do you want to order?
我們來吃冷玉米吧
Let's do chilly babycorn.
“每公斤1000盧比! ”
"Rs. 1000 per Kg!"
計劃辭職的人，不要吃玉米粒！
People planning to quit their job, don't eat babycorn!
夥計，我聽說會有大筆資金流入，好嗎？
Dude, I was told there's going to be an influx of money, ok?
要發工資了，我要訂購嬰兒玉米！
I'm going to get a salary and hence, I'm ordering babycorn!
我們也給納文點點東西吧
-Let's order something for Naveen too.
是的，他一定在路上了
Yeah, he must be on his way.
納文來不了了
Naveen's not going to be able to make it.
曼達爾？
-Mandal?
他在哪兒？
Where is he?
事實上..
Actually...
是他讓我來這兒的
He's the one who requested me to come here.
他..
He...
不得不馬上離開
... had to leave urgently.
去哪裏？
But where?
請去機場
Airport please.
這對他來說是一個非常艱難的決定
It was a very tough decision for him.
他很傷心
He was very sad.
還哭了
He waas even crying.
你說真的? 他哭了？
Are you serious? He was crying?
我是說，電話裏聽不出來吧
I mean, you can't really tell on the phone, can you?
但是他的聲音..
But his voice...
聽起來很沈重
... sounded heavy.
但他為什麼不打電話給我們？
But why didn't he call us?
他很匆忙，所以打電話給他最好的朋友
He was in a hurry. So called up his best friend.
麵對你們他一定很難過
He must be feeling really bad about facing you guys.
他一定感到很內疚
He must be feeling very guilty.
你能開快一點嗎？
Could you please drive a little faster?
否則，我就要錯過我的航班了！
Or else, I'm going to miss my flight!
先生，你看這裏的交通有多堵！
Sir, you see how there's so much traffic here!
還有另外一條路可以通過昌迪瓦利
There's this one other way via Chandivali
我們要走那邊嗎？
Should we try that?
能準時到達機場嗎？
Will it get us to the airport on time?
那裏不會堵車吧？
There won't be any traffic there?
我們可以去碰碰運氣
We can find that out, only once, we take that road.
但是如果我們堵在這裏
But if we stay stuck here, in this traffic...
那肯定是趕不上飛機了！
Then you'll definitely miss your flight!
好吧，那我們就走你說的路
Alright then, let's try that one, then.
他不接電話
He's not answering his phone.
他不會接的
He won't.
他現在肯定已經登記入住了
He must've even checked in, by now.
你可以在他從德裏回來後的第二天和他談談
You can talk to him, when he gets back from Delhi, day after.
來吧，開心點，夥計們！
Come on, cheer up guys!
相信我，他愛你
Trust me. He loves you.
他總是跟我提起你們倆
He always spoke to me about the two of you.
打擾一下! 我們的酒杯呢？
Excuse me! Our pitcher?
喝吧，夥計們！
Drink guys!
尤吉，你已經辭職了，這不是個問題嗎？
Yogi, you've quit your job. Isn't that going to be a problem now?
我明天就回去
I'll go back tommorow.
我會告訴他們今天是荷爾蒙作祟
I'll tell them, I went through some hormonal problem!
我以前也這麼做過
I have done this before.
你的手機呢? 灑進咖啡了，對吧？
What about your phone? It got spilled on, with coffee, didn't it?
別提電話了，他燙傷了我的腿
Forget the phone. He burned my leg.
都燙紅了
It's become all red!
還要瞞著桑亞塗藥膏！
Have to keep applying burnol, without letting Soumya know about it!
讓我用啤酒再給你們講一遍
Let me explain it to you, with beer today.
它不會燙傷你，隻會灑出來
It won't burn, even if it spills.
你回來了！
You're back!!!
我就知道你會來的！
I knew it, you'd come!
這個混蛋一直說得好像你已經死了一樣！
This motherf**ker's been talking as if you've died!
你錯過了航班？
You missed your flight?
冇有錯過，離開了！
Didn't miss it. Left it!
為什麼? 機場冇有酒吧嗎？
Why? Aren't there any bars at the airport?
你以為我會為了啤酒放棄去北京嗎？
You think I let go off Beijing for beer?
我回來是為了創業
I came back for the start-up.
別擔心，坐下
Don't worry. Sit down.
服務員，再來一杯
Waiter, one more glass please.
納文怎麼了？
What'd happened Naveen?
拉傑問我是否確定，我們的想法是“百萬分之一” ？
Rajat asked me if I was sure, that our idea is "one in a million"?
隻是我不確定
It's just that, I wasn't sure.
你現在確定了？
So you're sure, now?
不，現在還不確定
No, not sure even now.
但是後來我想，如果我們辭掉工作去嘗試，我們可能會成功，也可能不會
But then I thought, if we quit our jobs and try, we might succeed, or we might not.
但是如果我們不嘗試，那麼我們肯定不會成功
But if we don't try, then we'll definitely not succeed.
所以基本上，這個故事的寓意是..
So basically, the moral of the story is...
我們都是啤酒，混蛋！
We're all beers, motherf**kers!
好了，是時候保護你的手機了！
OK, time to safeguard your phones!
讓我們先幹杯
Lets bottoms up first.
但是冇有玻璃杯，尤吉！
But I don't have a glass, Yogi!
- 拿著這個-那你呢？
-Take this one. -And what about you?
我用這個喝
I'll drink from the pitcher!
幹杯! 幹杯！
Cheers! Cheers!
等我一下，夥計們
Give me a second guys.
所以你明天就辭職？
- So you're quitting your job tomorow?
是的，怎麼樣了？
Yes Chatty, tell me?
不一定是明天，因為我還要和桑亞商量一下！
Not really tomorrow, becasue I still have to discuss it with Soumya!
你為什麼要結婚？
Why would you get married, dude?
又冇有人逼你結婚，難道是為了啪啪啪？
It's not cumpolsory, to get arrange married, for sex?
尤吉，不是的
Yogi, it's not really for sex
桑亞是一個很好的人！
Soumya's also a very good person!
發生了什麼？
What happened?
八卦剛打電話來
Chatty just called.
阿克希爾給我坑了
Akhil gave us the wrong information!
我們的名字不在獲勝者名單上！
Our name's not on the winner's list!
我就知道！
I knew it!
四號酒店的家夥是一群混蛋
Hostel 4 guys are the biggest douchebags!!!
狗娘養的整晚都在吃麵包
Motherf**kers ate bread savouries all night long
然後把他們的賬單加到我的食堂賬戶上！
And then added their bills to my canteen account!
我恨死四號酒店的人了！
I hate hostel 4 guys.
但是等等..
But wait...
現在我的薪水怎麼辦？
What about my salary now?